

https://corentin-ducloux.netlify.app 🖸











## **SKILL SET**

■ Data Visualisation: Python (plotly) - PowerBI - R (ggplot2)

**Data Manipulation:** SQL - Python (polars, pandas, duckdb)

Machine Learning: Sklearn - Tidymodels

**Data Apps Frameworks**: Streamlit - Shiny

↑↑ Devops: Git - Github Actions - Docker

Reporting: Quarto - Rmarkdown - LATEX

Cloud Data Warehousing: Snowflake

**Web Development:** HTML - CSS

I am currently working as a **Data Engineer** at Edvance in the commissioning team, in Lyon. With several internships completed within Data/Analytics teams in the industry, I have accumulated more than a year of hands-on experience in the field. Feel free to check out my website and projects at <u>corentin-ducloux.netlify.app</u>!

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

April 2024 → Sep. 2024



EDF: Data Engineer (Internship)

- **♀** Tours
- Refactoring of a dataviz app from R to Python, with a GitLab CI/CD pipeline and various added features.
   Development of a Shiny app generating automated reports related to the loss of control cabinets for the
- Development of a Shiny app generating automated reports related to the loss of control cabinets for the Hinkley Point C EPR. The tool saved about 4400 hours of work and 330k€.
- Creation of data pipelines using duckdb + polars, pydantic for data validation.

April 2023 → Aug. 2023



Safran Seats: Data Analyst & BI Developer (Internship)

**♀** Issoudun

- Production ready Python solution ensuring cross-tool (ERP, PLM, CRM) data quality and consistency.
- Tables, views and stored procedures migration from SQL Server to Snowflake as part of the new Data Warehousing infrastructure.
- Lead time analysis and manufacturing order tracking dashboard on PowerBI.
- Deployed 4+ functional and optimized dashboards on the company PowerBI Report Server.

June 2022 → Aug. 2022



Crédit Agricole Titres: Data Analyst

**9** Mer

- Dashboard to manage banking mobility activity using PowerQuery & PowerBI.
- Development of a prioritization system for processing shared email inboxes using VBA.
- · Automation of multi-file Word exports to PDF.

### **EDUCATION**

2022 - 2024

#### Data & Business Intelligence master's degree

University of Tours

- Project: Wine prices estimation app using Streamlit and Docker ightarrow ightharpoonup wine-scraping
- Project: Econometric analysis of smartphone pricing efficiency  $\rightarrow \mathbf{Q}$  smart-specs

| Big Data | RDBMS | Software Engineering with Python | Microeconometrics | Machine Learning | Data Mining | Exploratory Data Analysis | Web scraping | APIs |

2018 — 2022

### Business economics bachelor's degree

**♀** University of Tours

| Econometrics | Statistics | Probabilities | R | Python | Microeconomics | Excel | VBA |

# LANGUAGES

French – (Native)

English – (C1)

→ TOEIC®: 920/990

# INTERESTS

Mathematics and computer science courses Practice of synth and electric bass Swimming

### SOFT SKILLS

Interpersonal Skills Stress Management Popularization of technical subejcts